Finding Aid for the Ken Englund Papers PASC.0157
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ken Englund papers
1933-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Englund, Ken
PASC.0157
12.5 Linear Feet (25 boxes)
Ken Englund was a magazine writer when he began writing sketches and special material for vaudeville, radio, stage and film. The collection consists of script material for motion pictures, television, stage, and radio written by Englund and his collaborators.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 1971.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9912179873606533
Biography
Englund was born in Chicago, Illinois on May 6, 1911. He began his career as a magazine writer and started writing material for vaudeville routines, radio shows, stage musicals, and film. Film projects include The Big Broadcast (1938), No No Nanette (1940), This Thing Called Love (1941), and The Secret Life of Walter Mitty (1947). Englund served as lead writer for Dr. Joyce Brothers' television series and contributed scripts to television programs including The Jackie Gleason Show, My Three Sons, That Girl, and The Loretta Young Show. He also served as president of the Writers Guild of America, West. Englund died on March 3, 1993.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of material related to the career of writer, Ken Englund. Primarily includes scripts for motion pictures (produced and unproduced), television, stage, and radio containing the radio programs The Armour Hour (1933-35), Joe Penner (1937), National Biscuit Show (1937), and The Ken Murray Show (1937). Also includes personal papers and project files including treatments and story ideas written by Englund and his collaborators.
Radio writers -- United States -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Radio scripts; Television writers -- United States -- Archives.; Englund, Ken--Archives.
- ALMA MATER - U.S.A., Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 13)
  Scope and Contents note
  Original Format for television series by Ken Englund, November 27, 1965.
- AMERICA MARCHES ON, Radio scripts (Box 15, Folder 17)
  Comedy show by Irving Brecher and Ken Englund, no date.
- AMERICAN BEAUTY #3, Television scripts (Box 18, Folder 8)
  "The Right Decisions" script by Ken Englund, July 17, 1951.
- ANGELS WEEP (aka PINK EYED MAN FROM NASSAU STREET), Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Story and Treatment by Ken Englund and Rouben Mamoulian, no date.
- ANGELS WEEP (aka PINK-EYED MAN FROM NASSAU STREET), Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 8)
  Original story and Treatment by Ken Englund, April 3, 1942.
- ANKLE BRACELET,., no date (Box 22, Folder 4)
  By Ken Englund.
- APPLE BLOSSOM - DRIVE IN, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 9)
  Cast list and Story for program number one, no date.
- ARMFUL OF WHITE ROSES, AN, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 11)
  Dictated outline of film dramatization, based on Eleanora Duse, written by Ken Englund, 11-18-55.
- ARMOUR HOUR, THE, Radio scripts (Box 1)
  Scripts for March 17, 1933 through December 29, 1933. Some with pencil notes. Starring Phil Baker.
- ARMOUR HOUR, THE, Radio scripts (Box 2)
  Scripts for January 5, 1934 through October 19, 1934. Some with pencil notes. Starring Phil Baker.
- ARMOUR HOUR, THE, Radio scripts (Box 3)
  Scripts for November 2, 1934 through May 31, 1935. Some with pencil notes. Starring Phil Baker.
- ARMOUR HOUR, THE, Radio scripts (Box 4)
  Scripts for June 7, 1935 through July 26, 1935. Folders 1 - 4. Some with pencil notes. Starring Phil Baker.
- ARTISTS AND MODELS ABROAD (1938), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 18, Folder 12)
  Revised sequence "C" by Ken Englund, April 30, 1938.
- AXMAN, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 19)
  Story idea of New Orleans by Ken Englund, no date.
- BEAUTIFUL GIRLS WANTED, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Notes for film story by Ken Englund, July 30, 1957.
- BEWITCHED, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 16)
  Three story outlines by Ken Englund for television series. No date.
- BIG BROADCAST OF 1938, THE, Radio scripts (Box 10)
  Scripts including inserts, additions, revisions, and new sequences, written by Ken Englund. Folders 3 - 5.
- BIG BROADCAST OF 1938, THE, Radio scripts (Box 15, Folder 19)
  Added and Revised Scenes by Ken Englund, December 28, 1937.
- BLUE RIBBON TOWN, Radio scripts (Box 15, Folder 16)
  Script, July 31, 1943. Starring Groucho Marx, Gregory Ratoff, and others.
- BROADWAY BEAT, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 22)
  Original Format for television series by Ken Englund, no date.
- BROADWAY VERSUS HOLLYWOOD, Television scripts (Box 15, Folder 18)
  Fourth Draft by Ken Englund for television on Columbia Broadcasting System, no date.
- BY MOONLIGHT, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Original Screenplay by Nat Perrin and Ken Englund, June 20, 1939.
- CHARMED LIFE, A, Stageplays (Box 20, Folder 8)
  First Draft, long version for a play by Ken Englund, February 21, 1959. Includes extensive hand-written notes, corrections, and additions to the draft.
- CHARMED LIFE, A, Stageplays (Box 20, Folder 10)
  Uncut First Rough Draft by Ken Englund, December 8, 1958. Not corrected, contains errors as copied from handwritten version.
- CHARMED LIFE, A, Stageplays (Box 20, Folder 11)
  First Draft by Ken Englund, August 12, 1959. Edited copy, tentatively retitled "Hawaiian Eye - 36-24-36."
- CHARMED LIFE, A, Stageplays (Box 21, Folder 3)
  First draft, completely handwritten by Ken Englund, December 8, 1958. Tentatively titled "Cookoos Anonymous" includes notes and story descriptions.
- CHARMED LIFE, A, Stageplays (Box 21, Folder 4)
  First Draft, handwritten by Ken Englund, no date. Updated and edited from first handwritten script.
- CORRESPONDENCE, Personal Material (Box 20, Folder 9)
  Set of approximately fifteen letters from 1969-1972 to and from Ken Englund.
- CRUISE DIRECTOR, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Format for television show by Ken Englund.
- DARK ROAD, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Treatment by Ken Englund and Jack Hasty.
- DAY IN THE LIFE OF A HOLLYWOOD WRITER, A, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 11)
  Preliminary drafts by Ken Englund, no date. Includes suggested themes for series "Artists and Models."
- DEAR PHOEBE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 9)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund, no date.
- DEEP SEDUCTIVE WOUND, A,., no date (Box 22, Folder 1)
  A play by Ken Englund and Sidney Field, no date.
- DEEP SEDUCTIVE WOUND, A,., no date (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund and Sidney Field based on their stage play
- DEEP SEDUCTIVE WOUND, A,., no date (Box 22, Folder 3)
  A play by Ken Englund and Sidney Field with annotations.
- DOUBLE OR NOTHING, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Treatment idea by Ken Englund, June 25, 1941.
- DRAWERS FOR VARIOUS PROGRAMS, Personal Material (Box 15, Folder 12)
  Show summaries for Rinso-Lifebuoy, Joe Penner, National Biscuit Company, and Armour Hour.
- EDDIE FISHER SHOW, THE, Television scripts (Box 16, Folder 6)
  Shooting Script by Ken Englund for November 11, 1958.
- ENGLUND'S LONDON JOURNAL,., 1958 July 21-26 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Manuscript. Mayfair Hotel, London, Westminster
- EVERYTHING TO LIVE FOR, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Story Treatment by Ken Englund, no date.
- FACE, THE LOOK, THE FLAME, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 20)
  Story idea by Ken Englund for television series, no date.
- FALLING STAR, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Idea and Treatment by Ken Englund, May 22, 1941.
- FILE INDEX, Personal Material (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Index to Ken Englund collection. Includes summaries of Penner, Moore- Broderick, Murray, and Baker shows. Also includes list of audition scripts.
- FOR LAUGHING OUT LOUD, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 6)
  Treatment and Screen Story for Ritz Brothers by Ken Englund, no date.
- FORM DIVINE, THE,., no date (Box 22, Folder 6)
  A comedy mystery for the screen by Ken Englund.
- FORM DIVINE, THE,., no date (Box 22, Folder 7)
  A comedy mystery by Ken Englund.
- GIRL IN THE FISH BOWL, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 21)
  Story Treatment by Ken Englund and Robert Smith, no date.
- GOLDEN GOOSE, THE, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 13, Folder 4)
- GOLDEN GOOSE, THE,., no date (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund.
- GOOD GIRLS GO TO PARIS (1939), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Second Draft by Gladys Lehman and Ken Englund, December 29, 1928. Final Script by Gladys Lehman and Ken Englund, January 31, 1939. Released by Columbia Pictures.
- GOOD SAM (1948), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Shooting Script by Leo McCarey and Ken Englund, July 7, 1947. Released by RKO Pictures.
- GOOD SAM (1948), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Screen Notes by Leo McCarey and Ken Englund, March 5, 1947. Released by RKO Pictures.
- GOODNIGHT SWEET SHAKESPEARE,., no date (Box 22, Folder 9)
  A sketch by Ken Englund.
- GOODNIGHT SWEET SHAKESPEARE,., no date (Box 22, Folder 10)
  A sketch by Ken Englund. Rough draft.
- GREAT MANHUNT, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Format for television series by Ken Englund, no date.
- GREAT MANHUNT, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 14)
- GUSSI'S GREAT TRAIN ROBBERY, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 18, Folder 3)
  Story idea and character descriptions by Ken Englund, no date.
- HE AND SHE,., 1948 October (Box 22, Folder 11)
  By Ken Englund. Staging, choreography, and overall direction by Agnes De Mille.
- HE AND SHE,., 1948 December (Box 22, Folder 12)
- HE AND SHE,., 1948 October (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Playlets, and songs being considered for development and inclusion in "He and She."
- HE AND SHE,., no date (Box 23, Folder 2)
  Lyrics.
- HE AND SHE,., 1948 October (Box 23, Folder 3)
- HEART INTEREST, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Treatment by Ken Englund, no date.
- HER HONOR BELONGS TO ME, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Presentation and Format for television series by Danny Arnold and Ken Enlund, September 2, 1965.
- HER HONOR BELONGS TO ME, Television scripts (Box 17, Folder 17)
  Pilot Script by Danny Arnold and Ken Englund for Screen Gems, October 18, 1965.
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 January-April (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Story outlines (Ken Englund, Zion Myers and Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 April 10-May 2 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Story outlines (Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., no date (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Story outline (Ken Englund and Zion Myers).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 March 3 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Synopsis (Ken Englund and Zion Myers).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 March 10 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Treatment of balance of story following sequence "B" (revised Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 April 18 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  Script (Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 April 3 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  Story outline (Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 March 30-April 17 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  Story outline and sequence "A" (Allan Scott).
- HERE COME THE WAVES,., 1944 August 12 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Dialogue continuity. Produced and directed by Mark Sandrich.
- HIP-HIP-HIPPLEFINGER!, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 10)
  Story for Danny Kaye by Ken Englund, Everett Freeman, and Mel Shavelson, August 22, 1946.
- HOLLYWOOD HOOK AND LADDER, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Outline and Format for television series by Ken Englund, no date.
- I LOATHE LOVE,., no date (Box 23, Folder 12)
  A sentimental comedy by Ken Englund.
- JOE PENNER, Radio scripts (Box 8)
  Scripts for January 24, 1937 through March 28, 1937. Folders 3 - 5,some with pencil notes. Starring Joe Penner.
- JOE PENNER, Radio scripts (Box 9)
  Scripts for April 4, 1937 through June 27, 1937. Folders 1 - 3, some with pencil notes. Starring Joe Penner.
- JOE PENNER, Radio scripts (Box 9)
  Original Joe Penner scripts, from January through June 1937. Folders 4 & 5.
- JOE PENNER, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Miscellaneous scripts from May 16, 1937 through June 6, 1937.
- KEN MURRAY THEATRE GUILD, Radio scripts (Box 7)
  Annotated/ handwritten audition scripts, undated.
- KID-STUFF,., no date (Box 23, Folder 13)
  A screen story by Ken Englund.
- LIKE MOTHER, LIKE DAUGHTER, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Original story for a musical to star Marilyn Monroe and Mae West, by Jackie Gleason and Ken Englund, September 27, 1953. Incomplete, 31 pages.
- LIVE-WIRE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 1)
- LONE STAR, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Story idea by Ken Englund, no date. Includes story outline, general remarks and character listing.
- LOVE SONG,., no date (Box 23, Folder 14)
  A story for the screen by Ken Englund.
- MADCAP MARY MOONEY, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Synopsis for a romantic comedy screenplay by Groucho Marx and Ken Englund, no date.
- MARX BROTHERS, THE, Radio scripts (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Preliminary scripts and revisions by Ken Englund, no date. Also includes outline of radio program.
- MENACE!, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 20, Folder 3)
- MICKEY'S HOLLYWOOD PREMIERE, Radio scripts (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Audition Script for The Lever Brothers, written by Ken Englund, no date.
- MISCELLANEOUS IDEAS, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Handwritten notes by Ken Englund discussing several ideas, plot concepts, and production materials, no date.
- MODEL GIRL, THE (aka MAD AVENUE), Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 18)
- MOTHER WAS A MARINE, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 19, Folder 5)
  First Draft Screenplay by Ken Englund, March 10, 1950.
- NATIONAL BISCUIT SHOW, Radio scripts (Box 7)
  Scripts for February 5, 1937 through May 30, 1937. Folders 3 - 6, some with pencil notes. Starring Helen Broderick and Victor Moore.
- NATIONAL BISCUIT SHOW, Radio scripts (Box 8)
  Original scripts for February, 1937 through June, 1937. Starring Helen Broderick and Victor Moore.
- NATIONAL BISCUIT SHOW, Radio scripts (Box 8)
  Scripts for June 6, 1937 through June 20, 1937. Starring Helen Broderick and Victor Moore.
- NATIONAL BISCUIT SHOW, Radio scripts (Box 16)
  Scripts for January 8, 1937 through May 16, 1937. Folders 3 and 4, some with pencil notes. Starring Helen Broderick and Victor Moore.
- NEW FACES OF 1937 (1937), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Incomplete Final Script. Released by RKO Radio Pictures. Includes changes to be inserted into script.
- NO, NO, NANETTE (1940), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  General notes, story continuations, and estimating scripts by Ken Englund, June 6,1940 through August 24, 1940.
- NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH (1941), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Script by Don Hartman and Ken Englund, March 29, 1941. Released by Paramount Pictures.
- OPERATION AIR STRIP, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 18, Folder 6)
  Treatment by Ken Englund, January 16, 1954.
- PACKARD HOUR, Radio scripts (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Script for September 14, 1937. Guest starring the Marx Brothers.
- PAIR OF STAR CROSS'D LOVERS, A, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 5)
  Treatment for film drama by Ken Englund, no date.
- PEOPLE IN GLASSHOUSES, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 10)
  Original story for the screen by Ken Englund, no date.
- PERSONAL LETTER FROM GROUCHO MARX, Personal Material (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Letter for Ken Englund, from Groucho Marx signed on his personal stationary, dated November 27, 1946.
- POWER OF ATTORNEY LETTER, Personal Material (Box 17, Folder 9)
  Letter containing seven signatures which allow Ken Englund to be their attorney on January, 1962.
- RAY BOLGER TELEVISION PILOT FILM, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 19, Folder 12)
  Pilot script by Ken Englund, July 11, 1953, to star Ray Bolger.
- RAY MILLAND SHOW, THE, Television scripts (Box 18, Folder 10)
  "Apron Strings" script by Ken Englund for June 30, 1954.
- RAY MILLAND SHOW, THE, Television scripts (Box 18, Folder 11)
  "Silver Cord" show by Ken Englund for July 9, 1954.
- RAY MILLAND SHOW, THE,., 1954 July 15 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  "The silver cord" by Ken Englund.
- REPAID (aka HIDDEN ASSETS), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  First Draft Screenplay by Gladys Lehman and Ken Englund, November 14, 1938.
- RINGS ON HER FINGERS (1942), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Revised Shooting Final by Ken Englund, November 29, 1941. Released by Fox.
- RINGS ON HER FINGERS (1942), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Revised Final by Ken Englund, October 24, 1941. Released by Fox.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 4)
  Scripts for March 24, 1936 through March 31, 1936. Three items, some with pencil notes. Starring Ken Murray.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 4)
  Scripts for March, 1936 through December, 1936. Folders 5 - 7, which include original scripts, and miscellaneous material (auditions, etc.) Starring Ken Murray.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 5)
  Scripts for April 7, 1936 through July 28, 1936. Some with pencil notes. Starring Ken Murray.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 6)
  Scripts for August, 4 1936 through November 24, 1936. Some with pencil notes. Starring Ken Murray.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 7)
  Scripts for December 1, 1936 through December 15, 1936. Three items, some with pencil notes. Starring Ken Murray.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Four scripts by Ken Englund, no date. Starring Al Jolson, Martha Raye, and Parkyakarkas. Guest starring George Jessel.
- RINSO & LIFEBUOY - KEN MURRAY, Radio scripts (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Script for November 24, 1936, starring Ken Murray.
- ROSEMARY OF THE RITZ, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 12)
  Plot Concept for comedy series by Ken Englund, June 20, 1956.
- ROSES ARE RED, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Treatment by Ken Englund, no date
- SECRET LIFE OF WALTER MITTY, THE (1947), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 17, Folder 15)
  Cut scenes by Ken Englund, titled "The Secret Life Of James Thurber," and produced by Samuel Goldwyn.
- SEND ANOTHER COFFIN, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Second Draft Continuity by Ken Englund, August 11, 1939, and drafts dated August 29, 1939 with name changes in the scripts.
- SEVEN FOOLISH BROTHERS, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 7)
  Script by Ken Englund, no date.
- SHOW BIZ, Television scripts (Box 18, Folder 4)
  Final Script by Ken Englund for October 6, 1955. Produced by NBC Studios and aired on October 9, 1955.
- SKETCH FOR PHIL BAKER, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 15)
  Sketch by Ken Englund, October 19, 1934.
- SO FEW FOR LOVE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 20, Folder 1)
- SON, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 21, Folder 2)
  Script, no author or date, containing handwritten notes on a corrected draft.
- SPECIAL DELIVERY, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Plot synopsis and notes by Don Hartman and Ken Englund.
- SPICE OF LIFE, THE,., no date (Box 23, Folder 16)
- SPICE OF LIFE, THE,., no date (Box 23, Folder 17)
- SPOOKS, THE, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Story concept by Frederic Sondern, Jr., no date. Also includes correspondence from Columbia Pictures protesting the title's use.
- SPRINGTIME IN THE ROCKIES (1942), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Revised Final by Walter Bullock, June 11, 1942. Releasedby Republic Pictures.
- SPRINGTIME IN THE ROCKIES (1942), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Temporary Script by Walter Bullock, May 7, 1942. Released by Republic Pictures.
- STAGESTRUCK,., no date (Box 23, Folder 18)
  Theme for a screen musical revue by Ken Englund.
- SUNNY (1942), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund, December 4, 1940. Released by RKO Pictures.
- SUNSET STRIP,., no date (Box 25, Folder 2)
  By Ken Englund. Revised version.
- SWEET ROSIE O'GRADY (1943), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  Final Script by Ken Englund, November 25, 1942. Released by Fox.
- TAKE ME OUT TO THE BALL GAME, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 17, Folder 23)
  Format for television comedy by Ken Englund, no date.
- THEATRICAL & ADVERTISING BACKGROUND/ STATISTICS, Personal Material (Box 21, Folder 5)
  List of screen, radio, and stage credits by Ken Englund, includes handwritten notes. No date.
- THERE'S THAT WOMAN AGAIN (1938), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  Revised pages, October 1, 1938.
- THINGS BEGAN TO HAPPEN, Projects (treatments, story ideas) for film/television (Box 15, Folder 14)
  Story Outline proposed by Mr. Fields for a motion picture, February 5, 1938.
- THIS THING CALLED LOVE (1940), Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Final Script by Ken Englund, July 29, 1940. Released by Columbia Pictures.
- TOUBIE'S MONUMENT,., 1958 March 3 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund. Second draft.
- TOUBIE'S MONUMENT,., 1958 February 19 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund. First draft.
- TOUBIE'S MONUMENT,., 1957 October 30 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  Treatment by Ken Englund. First Draft. Two items.
- TOUR D'AMOUR, Stageplays (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Musical play by Charles Henderson and Ken Englund, no date.
- TOUR D'AMOUR, Stageplays (Box 19, Folder 3)
- TOUR D'AMOUR, Stageplays (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Musical play by Charles Henderson and Ken Englund. Includes handwritten production notes.
- TOUR D'AMOUR,., no date (Box 24, Folder 1)
  A musical play. Music and lyrics by Charles Henderson. Book by Ken Englund.
- TUBIE'S MONUMENT, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  First Draft Screenplay by Ken Englund, February 19, 1958.
- TWIN STARS, Radio scripts (Box 15, Folder 20)
  Revised script, January 29, 1937.
- TWO TICKETS TO BROADWAY, Screenplays (produced/unproduced) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  Screenplay by Ken Englund, November 17, 1949.
- VACANCY, Stageplays (Box 19, Folder 2)
  By Ken Englund, no date.
- VACANCY,., no date (Box 24, Folder 7)